[
  {
    "question": "Obesity",
    "answer": "A complex disease involving an excessive amount of body fat; classified by a body mass index of 30 or greater.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "207705fa-b420-45d8-999a-e8680cf64c5c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Kinesiology",
    "answer": "Study of movement as it relates to anatomy and physiology.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "09ca169c-5001-4fd8-8278-31eddfa8119d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Evidence-based practice",
    "answer": "A practice that relies on evidence for guidance and decision-making and includes developing individual expertise, staying current on the best sources of external evidence (e.g., peer-reviewed research), and prioritizing client values and expectations.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "3ecddf25-7fe9-4a49-bc7a-c0a9ec22a8c3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Musculoskeletal system",
    "answer": "The combined, interworking system of all muscles and bones in the body.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "f1dbccdd-ce17-4788-a835-fb1564140b66"
  },
  {
    "question": "Deconditioned",
    "answer": "A state of lost physical fitness, which may include muscle imbalances, decreased flexibility, and a lack of core and joint stability.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "53d6e85c-cc86-4ed6-b22c-6e52acf03418"
  },
  {
    "question": "Overweight",
    "answer": "A body weight greater than what is considered within normal standards; a body mass index of 25.0 to 29.9.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "edda9f35-e674-42a8-bc30-f1dd3829675b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Muscle imbalance",
    "answer": "When muscles on each side of a joint have altered length-tension relationships.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "1585d3ba-e93f-43fc-adf5-6d7b2fe12fa4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Joint stability",
    "answer": "The support provided by tissues surrounding a joint to maintain and provide control during movement.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "69885164-99e9-48e7-8028-2e020f58f3a0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Socioeconomic status",
    "answer": "The social standing of a person or group that includes education, income, and occupation.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "98ce1bd9-63a1-4daa-8f90-eb4c4c048860"
  },
  {
    "question": "Morbidity",
    "answer": "The state of having a disease.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "11c5c351-10ed-47c7-857c-cfec64517d95"
  },
  {
    "question": "Mortality",
    "answer": "A state or a risk of death or dying.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "eb277a05-984e-4335-a933-dd828f18488f"
  },
  {
    "question": "Homeostasis",
    "answer": "The process by which the human body strives to maintain a relatively stable equilibrium.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "87cc5d5d-8e14-4810-ab40-45dfa4f01928"
  },
  {
    "question": "Risk factor",
    "answer": "Any attribute, characteristic, or exposure of an individual that increases the likelihood of developing a disease or injury.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "45e09a37-8d92-4fdc-89f3-4398b0f154f1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cholesterol",
    "answer": "A waxy, fatlike substance found in bodily cells.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "1e0d9bb1-acde-4a43-9756-946349647770"
  },
  {
    "question": "Stroke",
    "answer": "A sudden lack of blood supply to the brain, caused by either a blockage in an artery or ruptured blood vessel.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "733006c1-42d7-4f21-b09c-af34008128cf"
  },
  {
    "question": "Heart attack",
    "answer": "The action that occurs when an artery supplying the heart with blood and oxygen becomes blocked; medically known as a myocardial infarction.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "cc0b9f2e-83b9-441a-a525-88ce71637426"
  },
  {
    "question": "Heart failure",
    "answer": "A condition in which the heart can’t pump enough blood to meet the body’s needs.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "f2383455-f60f-42b2-a1fe-97c3e8119422"
  },
  {
    "question": "Heart valve problem",
    "answer": "A condition that occurs when one or more heart valves do not function properly, causing shortness of breath and reduced oxygen supply to the body.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "9eb87898-b557-47b9-947e-6fec1ad7eecc"
  },
  {
    "question": "Arrhythmia",
    "answer": "A problem with the rate or rhythm of a person’s heartbeat. The heart beats too quickly, too slowly, or with an irregular pattern.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "40dbef2a-8329-44c2-9943-d41ba39eb0df"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ischemic heart disease",
    "answer": "A category of heart-related problems caused by the narrowing of coronary arteries, which supply blood and oxygen to the heart muscle.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "1605c7ae-dddc-4ab1-ad24-85e2cb2bc300"
  },
  {
    "question": "Atherosclerosis",
    "answer": "The processes by which plaque is formed in arteries leading to reduced blood flow.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "76f53185-79dc-41d0-adee-353656b21b79"
  },
  {
    "question": "Physical activity",
    "answer": "Bodily movement that results in energy expenditure and encompasses many modes and intensities. Movement that is not structured exercise such as recreational pursuits (e.g., golfing, gardening, and walking a dog).",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "f5a42127-59f8-4173-aea3-e6c4851684f2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hypertension",
    "answer": "Consistently elevated blood pressure.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "6f017d87-bb9d-4c7e-9e72-06826bda29b9"
  },
  {
    "question": "Systolic blood pressure (SBP)",
    "answer": "The pressure in arteries and other blood vessels when the heart is contracting; the first (top) number recorded.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "a488321c-86d8-40e0-ac21-a6e7d3b3623e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Diastolic blood pressure (DBP)",
    "answer": "The pressure in arteries and other blood vessels when heart is at rest or between beats; the second (bottom) number recorded.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "b7f314ee-85a2-4062-907d-9a7083c967e0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Diabetes",
    "answer": "Chronic metabolic disorder, caused by insulin deficiency, which impairs carbohydrate usage and enhances usage of fat and protein.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "61844184-9bfb-48e4-a394-f378dc6712d3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Glucose",
    "answer": "The simplest form of carbohydrate used by the body for energy.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "8bc4e8e3-4252-4d2e-9090-537c5e427cdf"
  },
  {
    "question": "Insulin resistance",
    "answer": "The inability of the cells to respond to insulin; occurs in type 2 diabetes.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "262ce6b2-276f-4864-a032-e23334582d50"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cancer",
    "answer": "A group of diseases involving abnormal cell growth with the potential to invade or spread to other parts of the body.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "41e79a49-49b2-4ef1-af4d-77613d808217"
  },
  {
    "question": "Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)",
    "answer": "A general term used to describe progressive lung diseases, including emphysema, chronic bronchitis, and refractory (nonreversible) asthma.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "a5cbeb11-e1ef-43ed-a558-382b01bf0984"
  },
  {
    "question": "Endorphins",
    "answer": "A group of hormones secreted by the brain that provides a variety of physiological functions, such as reducing the perception of pain.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "71a79bd6-ed60-4afa-b256-8307becdb005"
  },
  {
    "question": "Skeletal muscle",
    "answer": "The type of muscle tissue that connects to bones and generates the forces that create movement.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "86633ffd-e715-4978-9d37-d2116adec5fc"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sprain",
    "answer": "A stretching or tearing of ligaments.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "faa4317e-b6b1-4659-bc84-4fe880b1d270"
  },
  {
    "question": "Plantar fasciitis",
    "answer": "An inflammation of the fibrous tissue (plantar fascia) along the bottom of the foot, which often results in intense heel pain.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "b124b4b9-d581-458f-a40e-829493bfb2e7"
  },
  {
    "question": "Patellar tendonitis",
    "answer": "An injury or inflammation of the tendon that connects the patella (kneecap) to the tibia (shin bone).",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "904a5458-218d-45fa-a539-ab1ea0301486"
  },
  {
    "question": "Anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) tear",
    "answer": "A stretch, partial tear, or complete tear of the anterior cruciate ligament of the knee.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "d7e02367-331a-43a7-b842-253826d7e4ea"
  },
  {
    "question": "Medial collateral ligament (MCL) tear",
    "answer": "A stretch, partial tear, or complete tear of the medial collateral ligament of the knee.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "e42e253b-d69f-4f2e-ac7b-c0dc6f3f14d9"
  },
  {
    "question": "Shoulder impingement syndrome",
    "answer": "Shoulder pain caused by rotator cuff tissues rubbing against the acromion bone of the shoulder.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 1"
    ],
    "id": "4fdac913-4fc0-43f3-9ad0-88a6a1595439"
  },
  {
    "question": "Operational costs",
    "answer": "The various monetary requirements associated with the day-to-day running of a business.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 2"
    ],
    "id": "b3d69e5d-dde2-4fd4-89fb-33a789378a94"
  },
  {
    "question": "High-intensity interval training (HIIT)",
    "answer": "An exercise training method defined by intervals of near-maximal intensity broken up by relatively short rest periods.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 2"
    ],
    "id": "12dc4f7e-1fd4-46e6-86d9-ddf9581a1ee4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Adherence",
    "answer": "The level of commitment to a behavior or plan of action.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 2"
    ],
    "id": "2715b74c-7f96-4f19-9bc2-1723c0c7a371"
  },
  {
    "question": "Prospect",
    "answer": "An individual who has been identified as a potential client.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 2"
    ],
    "id": "15a3f152-bbde-4ce2-81c8-6ea72531db24"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sales process",
    "answer": "A system for learning about the needs of a potential client to be able to identify and present a number of solutions for those needs.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 2"
    ],
    "id": "ad1439eb-55fb-45b9-a046-cdedb80cd95f"
  },
  {
    "question": "Open-ended questions",
    "answer": "Nondirective questions that can’t be answered with a simple yes or no answer; they require critical thinking to formulate a response.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 2"
    ],
    "id": "e968b3b6-0887-4a7a-b044-f20b49ddbb1d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Working the ﬂoor",
    "answer": "A rapport-building technique where fitness professionals walk around the gym floor talking to members without overtly presenting a sale.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 2"
    ],
    "id": "ee38a2fb-a100-48c7-86bb-6fe5703bc4fa"
  },
  {
    "question": "Rapport",
    "answer": "A relationship in which two people understand each other’s ideas, have respect for one another, and communicate well.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 2"
    ],
    "id": "49f606ef-64d7-4668-bb19-c3071cee19ec"
  },
  {
    "question": "Forecasting",
    "answer": "A business management technique that helps predict how much work is needed to meet a revenue goal.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 2"
    ],
    "id": "d69aea72-a77c-40ec-b261-07957d2804e2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Unique selling proposition (USP)",
    "answer": "Highlighting unique skills or traits during a sales presentation that allow an individual to stand out from the competition.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 2"
    ],
    "id": "358c5f45-4386-4a53-b8f7-899cdc842b85"
  },
  {
    "question": "Brand",
    "answer": "A product or service identified by specific, unique characteristics.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 2"
    ],
    "id": "0aabc003-155e-4423-a1cb-e683da8bd596"
  },
  {
    "question": "SWOT analysis",
    "answer": "A professional development technique that helps individuals identify their personal strengths and weaknesses, opportunities for growth, and potential threats to success.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 2"
    ],
    "id": "1910e60b-74a6-45d5-a156-1ef08d4ffa58"
  },
  {
    "question": "Psychology",
    "answer": "An area of science that focuses on people, and in particular, how the mind and feelings may influence behaviors.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 3"
    ],
    "id": "0b048f21-aab0-41c0-8e19-ea098a150c55"
  },
  {
    "question": "Adherence",
    "answer": "The level of commitment to a behavior or plan of action.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 3"
    ],
    "id": "df506b15-3ef7-487f-8f8a-b6b82fd6972a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Motivation",
    "answer": "The intensity and direction of someone’s effort to participate in an activity or engage in a behavior.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 3"
    ],
    "id": "c05116e7-0320-4055-b21c-df21f343fa48"
  },
  {
    "question": "Socioeconomic status",
    "answer": "The social standing of a person or group that includes education, income, and occupation.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 3"
    ],
    "id": "8ac424bb-b436-43b9-ae99-71d9d0f0da94"
  },
  {
    "question": "Amotivation",
    "answer": "Describes when someone is not motivated to engage in an activity or behavior.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 3"
    ],
    "id": "57ce9afb-2fd5-4bab-a8a2-affcabe1ce53"
  },
  {
    "question": "Extrinsic motivation",
    "answer": "When someone participates in an activity or behavior for some type of reward or recognition from others.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 3"
    ],
    "id": "ff28d384-3456-4728-a8c0-2c245d17cc2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Intrinsic motivation",
    "answer": "When people engage in an activity or behavior because they feel a sense of satisfaction or enjoyment",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 3"
    ],
    "id": "54b89edb-428d-4287-bf91-cd53bffba429"
  },
  {
    "question": "Outcome goals",
    "answer": "Goals focused on the end result.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 3"
    ],
    "id": "2cca7ecf-7347-4715-9464-1d54b780ac6f"
  },
  {
    "question": "Process goals",
    "answer": "Refers to the process of goal pursuit.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 3"
    ],
    "id": "a8afd65a-77e8-4977-9cc6-3d36e88d0aed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Social support",
    "answer": "The intentional ways that people assist others in achieving a specific behavior.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 3"
    ],
    "id": "508554e2-36bf-4749-b464-3faf95752d3c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Social physique anxiety",
    "answer": "A specific form of anxiety that occurs in individuals who perceive that others could be negatively evaluating their physique.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 3"
    ],
    "id": "531ba957-00af-4722-81e2-51e325bcbac7"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ambivalence",
    "answer": "Describes a person’s state of mixed feelings about a situation.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 3"
    ],
    "id": "1c80e0b8-018d-42b5-a1f2-5e84d306ce2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Instrumental support",
    "answer": "The actions that directly facilitate a behavior to happen. In the context of exercise, instrumental support can include driving a person to a health club or paying for the gym membership.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 3"
    ],
    "id": "3c6d5bac-8be2-425c-952c-03bd1133d6bb"
  },
  {
    "question": "Emotional support",
    "answer": "The encouragement and positive reinforcement that is provided from an individual to another, which includes being caring, empathetic, and showing concern.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 3"
    ],
    "id": "28adf970-8c14-4bcb-b1fd-0957c3d10597"
  },
  {
    "question": "Empathy",
    "answer": "The ability to identify with another person’s feelings, attitudes, or thoughts.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 3"
    ],
    "id": "d59063a5-9290-4161-9221-59ef34dd8bc0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Informational support",
    "answer": "Providing accurate, current, and informative information.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 3"
    ],
    "id": "edd68d1c-5dc6-42f8-b6d1-0db376d571ad"
  },
  {
    "question": "Companionship support",
    "answer": "When someone engages in a behavior with an individual. This type of support is often observed in an exercise setting where people exercise with a friend or partner.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 3"
    ],
    "id": "20ddf048-ab45-4672-a021-6d2cd9e6c6aa"
  },
  {
    "question": "Self-esteem",
    "answer": "The way someone evaluates their own self-worth physically, emotionally, and socially.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 3"
    ],
    "id": "89751ee7-fdf1-4791-9da6-8af75a81c7e8"
  },
  {
    "question": "Body image",
    "answer": "The way someone views their physical self or visualizes their body.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 3"
    ],
    "id": "004ea320-90c9-4f0b-a547-4c37e0dd2682"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sleep apnea",
    "answer": "A sleep disorder in which a person’s breathing repeatedly stops and starts, which disrupts the body’s natural sleep cycle.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 3"
    ],
    "id": "c42e4124-7443-4909-9c87-95b778c32953"
  },
  {
    "question": "Physical activity",
    "answer": "Bodily movement that results in energy expenditure and encompasses many modes and intensities. Movement that is not structured exercise such as recreational pursuits (e.g., golfing, gardening, and walking a dog).",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "4809af00-ecc2-4f35-b3c8-325a7acbd25b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Adherence",
    "answer": "The level of commitment to a behavior or plan of action.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "2eb4a7a6-4f6f-4040-a73d-663e73e957be"
  },
  {
    "question": "Autonomy",
    "answer": "Acting in accordance with how one wants to behave.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "8c85320c-ed11-4598-ad80-97a3481db47e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Intrinsic motivation",
    "answer": "When people engage in an activity or behavior because they feel a sense of satisfaction.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "028479f0-3edb-4910-a15b-6b1ee0f1e740"
  },
  {
    "question": "Third space",
    "answer": "A communal space, separate from home or work, where the client experiences their own sense of identity and relationship to others.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "ef47b525-6259-4da3-a6b1-050d13bbdea6"
  },
  {
    "question": "Behavior change techniques (BCTs)",
    "answer": "Client interventions that are used to change some determinant of behavior.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "89ef3df6-ebbe-404b-9bfe-7189a36eab52"
  },
  {
    "question": "Self-efficacy",
    "answer": "One’s belief that they can complete a task, goal, or performance; also known as self-confidence.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "a749daac-0bd2-4802-a2a6-81dcaac14731"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ambivalence",
    "answer": "Describes a person’s state of mixed feelings about a situation.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "07ced0f9-c0e9-408a-9cd3-b4e80063990e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Self-monitoring",
    "answer": "Observing, measuring, and evaluating one’s own behavior, often in the form of a diary or log.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "176f5a06-54da-4a56-a7a8-01d841a71933"
  },
  {
    "question": "Determinants of behavior",
    "answer": "Refers to the psychological, social, or environmental factors that influence behavior.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "aec67081-012f-4528-a7ec-58d643082b2b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Intention",
    "answer": "A construct that captures motivational factors that influence behavior. It indicates how hard people are willing to try and how much effort they are planning to exert.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "d496e330-0072-4d90-bcd1-33bf589936a5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Self-determination theory",
    "answer": "A broad theoretical framework for the study of human motivation.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "ee5a2995-e30d-44f6-a1ce-55ca2dc656a8"
  },
  {
    "question": "Autonomous motivation",
    "answer": "When motives for exercise relate to valuing the outcome, when exercise is consistent with the client’s identity, or when the client enjoys exercise.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "e4373231-3057-47ed-b787-c98aa12d4f0c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Planning",
    "answer": "A concrete representation of when and where exercise will occur.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "fcbb131a-0708-4e2e-b722-1f7e784f365a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Attitude",
    "answer": "The degree to which a person has a favorable or unfavorable evaluation of the behavior of interest.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "148baafc-447a-470a-bf5a-c8f2ecc66df4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Outcome expectations",
    "answer": "The expected positive and negative consequences of a behavior.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "86651d59-a040-4f58-81c5-b6c3475029db"
  },
  {
    "question": "Stress",
    "answer": "The state of mental or emotional tension from demanding circumstances.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "e9519780-bf20-4dbc-a0e7-0edd6a5ddb64"
  },
  {
    "question": "Perceived behavioral control",
    "answer": "An evaluation of whether one has the means, resources, and opportunities to perform a behavior.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "7f149f60-c1a2-46c7-bd5d-251a6481dc57"
  },
  {
    "question": "Affective judgment",
    "answer": "Referring to expected pleasure or enjoyment.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "8029eea3-8f53-4d5a-b604-eddae17148f0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Subjective norms",
    "answer": "Belief that an important person or group of people will approve and support a behavior.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "32bd9d46-ad8f-4f09-acfa-87e5e2e2c37b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Precontemplation",
    "answer": "Client does not exercise and is not planning to start exercising within 6 months.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "ce4731a0-57de-4e78-9296-067db5fa9656"
  },
  {
    "question": "Contemplation",
    "answer": "When a person is thinking about implementing change but has not yet taken any steps to get started; an individual may take action within the next 6 months.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "4dfefea9-a829-47c2-9238-8e300ee8a2df"
  },
  {
    "question": "Preparation",
    "answer": "The client intends to act in the near future, usually within the next month.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "1d148dbe-fa6a-4752-98be-35e8caa23305"
  },
  {
    "question": "Action",
    "answer": "The client has made specific modifications in their exercise routine within the past 6 months.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "11f9bac9-ab6d-4cd6-8e27-53541cbb8cc5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Maintenance",
    "answer": "The client has been exercising for more than 6 months and is working to prevent relapse.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "e8d4540f-caa7-4a91-ba4c-b9c1b82d745a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Decisional balance",
    "answer": "Reflects the clients’ weighing of the pros and cons of changing.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "17ee1e29-7570-4f55-99e5-eebb9c16c86d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Empathy",
    "answer": "The ability to identify with another person’s feelings, attitudes, or thoughts.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "7c8f28a4-d26a-41cf-b68f-872fbeac2bd8"
  },
  {
    "question": "Rapport",
    "answer": "A relationship in which two people understand each other’s ideas, have respect for one another, and communicate well.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "afec3b2c-f2af-4ef0-9305-7b750bf9c871"
  },
  {
    "question": "Reflective listening",
    "answer": "The process of seeking to understand the meaning of the speaker’s words and restating the idea back to the speaker to confirm that they were understood correctly.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "a7a3938a-ceef-460c-9fc9-11956e502a58"
  },
  {
    "question": "Active listening",
    "answer": "Listening style that involves having genuine interest in what the speaker is saying; requires the listener to fully concentrate to understand the speaker’s message.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "d0bf6fe7-59e6-4e29-a9c3-665da8de0287"
  },
  {
    "question": "Closed-ended questions",
    "answer": "Directive questions that can be answered with one word, typically a yes or no.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "0e39803b-5ddd-4995-9a1c-1e9b95bbe7c2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Open-ended questions",
    "answer": "Nondirective questions that can’t be answered with a simple yes or no; they require critical thinking to formulate a response.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "4609177c-4446-40b4-8b72-e1181a012322"
  },
  {
    "question": "Collecting summaries",
    "answer": "Short sentences that continue the client’s thoughts and add momentum to the conversation.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "49fff9fc-ab49-4fbb-94e2-2b623d580663"
  },
  {
    "question": "Linking summaries",
    "answer": "Summaries that tie together information the client has presented, perhaps even from previous sessions.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "dd60eb28-c1eb-4e14-8ef0-d2e99fe067ff"
  },
  {
    "question": "Transitional summaries",
    "answer": "Summaries used to wrap up a session or announce a shift in focus.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "e2d0d855-7efb-486a-9fc6-135b2143bbdf"
  },
  {
    "question": "Affirmations",
    "answer": "Positive statements about character strengths.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "5d62a8fe-2171-4890-825c-9ea0252b0e6b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Motivational interviewing",
    "answer": "Client-centered, directive method for enhancing intrinsic motivation to change by exploring and resolving ambivalence.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "6fc53d8b-ab05-4150-8b58-0475aad35877"
  },
  {
    "question": "Self-discrepancy",
    "answer": "An internal conflict that occurs when an individual compares their actual self with their ideal self.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "d620d693-ea30-45e6-a52d-3a59c278b3a7"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sustain talk",
    "answer": "Talk that represents and predicts movement away from change.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "7eb99815-6d30-4373-ab57-023fdaf72ea3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Change talk",
    "answer": "Talk that reflects movement of the person toward behavior change.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "77c83f31-6352-4e23-893a-a7d1c161c4ad"
  },
  {
    "question": "Outcome goals",
    "answer": "Goals focused on the end result.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "c41cf649-3320-496b-a8b6-0b6091a86798"
  },
  {
    "question": "Process goals",
    "answer": "Tasks that are pursued to reach a final outcome.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "b987b437-d4d7-4735-84d0-c285a26dde80"
  },
  {
    "question": "Implementation intentions",
    "answer": "A behavior change technique that links a goal-directed response to situational cues by specifying when, where, and how to act.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "df3efb8c-c64a-4003-9d54-94f6188ae5f3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Coping plans",
    "answer": "A behavior change technique that involves anticipating barriers to goal action and proactively preparing strategies that prioritize intentional behavior over counterproductive habitual responses.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "a51203df-94e6-4113-ac3c-de3cf5e28f0c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Self-talk",
    "answer": "Internal dialogue in which the individual interprets feelings and perceptions, regulates and changes evaluations and convictions, and gives himself or herself instructions and reinforcement.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "2de0b742-cfdd-4d8c-a790-e8a3b8fa9886"
  },
  {
    "question": "Reverse listing",
    "answer": "Replacing negative statements with positive statements.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "fe0829fd-de55-4a70-82b9-53e345afb22c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Stopping",
    "answer": "The act of saying “stop” out loud to undesired statements.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "76bda9e1-2289-4fcd-bb74-c126af5043fa"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cognitive fusion",
    "answer": "When people believe the exact content of their own thoughts.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "0c6d3482-3f62-4c7a-9374-63cb577bdf63"
  },
  {
    "question": "Imagery",
    "answer": "The process created to produce internalized experiences.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "a63b222b-fb8a-4947-b14d-5cf57e7c3658"
  },
  {
    "question": "Appearance imagery",
    "answer": "When a person imagines appearance or health related outcomes.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "8b62f52d-d5ee-4ced-859c-b11ddbaa948a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Energy imagery",
    "answer": "When a person creates mental images that increase energy and/or relieve stress.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "c0f388d0-d6d3-4404-8bab-8b1865c02ab9"
  },
  {
    "question": "Technique imagery",
    "answer": "When individuals mentally rehearse their technique.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "7fbf88dd-a662-4e0d-b3a8-e36572d3da12"
  },
  {
    "question": "Psyching up",
    "answer": "The process to get oneself into a state of psychological readiness for performance.",
    "tags": [
      "cpt",
      "chapter 4"
    ],
    "id": "3a146c76-1f76-478b-8bf2-26408a67f05e"
  }
]